-By the way, Yuzuki. -Hmm?
-說起來 結月 -什麼事
You look very relaxed.
妳看起來相當悠閒嘛
But the blind date you postponed due to various reasons,
但是妳那個 因為各種狀況而延期的相親
isn't it today?
不就是今天嗎
The survival of this temple
這場相親不是事關重大嗎
relies on your blind date, doesn't it?
事關這所寺廟的存亡
MIKAZUKI TEMPLE I'm going to be late.
(三日月寺) 我快遲到了
Where is the blind date?
相親的地點在哪
Ryūkoku Temple
龍刻寺
In fact,
其實
we should have
我們本應該
moved out of this temple immediately.
立刻從這所寺廟裡搬出去的
My parents aren't here and the temple has no abbot.
因為我爸媽都不在 所以我家的寺廟沒有住持
Without an abbot, his family
住持不在的話 住持的家人
does not have the right to stay in the temple.
就沒有在寺廟裡 居住的權利
But if my blind date is successful,
但是如果我相親成功的話
it would be different if we could invite a new abbot.
能請來一個新的住持就不一樣了
Miss Yuzuki, are you going to marry someone you don't like
結月小姐 為了這所寺廟的存續
for the sake of this temple?
妳要和不喜歡的人結婚嗎
This is my own decision!
這是我自己做出的決定
I cannot let this temple be destroyed!
我絕對不能讓這所寺廟被毀掉
NO PARKING
(禁止停車)
BUS
(公車)
I still can't do it.
果然 我還是做不到嗎
I can't inherit this temple.
就憑我也想繼承這所寺廟…
Miss Yuzuki.
結月小姐
Isn't this a good time to change clothes?
這不是個換衣服的好時機嗎
Change your clothes here,
妳在這裡換好衣服
and let's go out when it stops at the next traffic light.
在車等下一個紅綠燈時我們就出去吧
But…
但是…
After we go out, we'll borrow this truck.
出去後我們就借這輛貨車一用
Of course, I have driving experience too.
當然啦 我也是有駕駛經驗的
Okay! Then let's quickly change up and break out!
好 那我們就趕緊換上衣服 然後破門而出吧
Understood.
收到
WORLDLY DESIRES
(世俗雜念)
(TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-)
《妙廟美少女》
EPISODE 4
(第4集)
After a lot of effort, they finally got out of the cargo box of this truck.
費了好大勁 他們總算是 從這輛貨車的貨箱裡逃出來了
Akemitsu and Yuzuki borrowed the truck
就這樣借來貨車的明光和結月
and rushed to Ryūkoku Temple.
迅速趕往相親地點“龍刻寺”
TRANSPORT COMPANY, BLACK SEABASS
(運輸公司 黑色公車)
Kiki, I don't want this temple to close down like this.
嬉嬉姐 我還是不希望這所寺廟 就這樣被廢掉
But it will take you three years to become an abbot.
但是 妳如果想要成為住持起碼需要三年呢
-This temple will be gone in a year… -I know.
-但這所寺廟還有一年就要… -我明白的
I decided to go on a blind date.
我…決定要去相親了
RYŪKOKU TEMPLE
(龍刻寺)
We made it!
我們趕上啦
Excuse me, I am here for today's blind date…
那個 我是今天來相親的…
Are you Miss Aoba Yuzuki?
您是蒼葉結月小姐嗎
-Akagami! -Yes, here!
-赤神 -我在
Thank you for taking me here.
謝謝你送我到這裡
-I'll take it from here! -Okay!
-接下來就交給我吧 -好的
There is no man in this world
這個世上是沒有男人
who would not be fascinated by Miss Yuzuki!
會不迷戀結月小姐的
TRANSPORT COMPANY, BLACK SEABASS Eh, is she laughing at me?
(運輸公司  黑色公車) 咦 我是被嘲笑了嗎
I'll go in now!
那我就進去囉
Good luck!
祝妳好運
In this case,
這樣一來
I will have to say goodbye to Miss Yuzuki.
我和結月小姐肯定就要分開了吧
If she gets married,
她如果結婚了
as a man, I cannot possibly continue to live with her.
我一個男人
Miss Yuzuki, I wish you all the happiness.
結月小姐 妳一定要幸福啊
Who are you?
您是哪位
What are you doing here?
我才想問你呢 偷偷摸摸的在這幹什麼呢
What do you mean?
您這是什麼意思
Since you're wearing a work uniform, you must be a temple staff.
既然你身穿作務衣 那麼你肯定是寺廟的人吧
Come and clean the yard quickly.
快點給我打掃院子去
Huh? I… I'm not…
啥 我…我不是…
I'm Aoba Yuzuki.
我叫蒼葉結月
Thank you very much for your hospitality.
非常感謝您今天的招待
And thank you for coming a long way.
彼此彼此 我才要感謝您遠道而來
RYUKOKU TEMPLE, THIRD SON, KIJOU HOUAN
(龍刻寺 三子 鬼城峯安)
My name is Kijou Houan.
我叫鬼城峯安
Nice to meet you.
還請您多多關照
You are very young.
您還真是年輕呢
Why would such a young girl come for a blind date?
為什麼您這麼年輕就要來相親呢
Because I really like Mikazuki Temple
因為我非常喜歡三日月寺
and everyone living there.
以及住在裡面的所有人
I see.
是這樣啊
Please do come and see.
請您一定要來寒舍看看
They are my proud family and friends.
他們都是我引以為傲的家人和朋友
They are gentle and warm,
既溫柔又溫暖
and incredibly reliable.
每個人都非常可靠
They must be cheering for me now, from far away.
他們現在也一定就在遠處
Here's one right here!
這麼近就有一個
Is it really him? Or just a look-alike?
是本人嗎 還是長得很像的人
I don't want to see
我不想看到
Miss Yuzuki with another man on a blind date.
結月小姐和其他男人相親的場景
But to see that stunning beauty again…
但是 能再看到這艷麗卓絕的身姿…
But!
但是…
Akagami,
赤神
look.
你看
Begone, worldly desires!
雜念退散 雜念退散
It's definitely him!
這絕對是本人啊
What's wrong?
您怎麼了
Are you still a bit nervous?
還是有些緊張嗎
No, I'm not.
沒...沒有
It's okay.
沒關係的
Just imagine your friends and family are nearby, watching over you.
您就想像您的家人和朋友 都在近處守護著您
I'm at a loss right now because he's right next to me.
正因為近在眼前 所以我才無所適從啊
What should I do? What was I going to say?
怎麼辦 我剛剛是想說什麼來著
Miss Yuzuki seems a bit flustered.
結月小姐有些手足無措
Oh no, I'm going to distract her!
不好 我在這裡會影響她
I need to hide quickly.
必須快點躲起來才行
Over here, over here!
這裡這裡
That nun from before?
是剛剛的尼姑…
HEAVENLY MATCH
(天作之合)
Since the matchmaker fell ill and couldn't come,
因為媒人突然生病不能親自到場
I, Akagami, will take their place for now.
所以就由鄙人赤神暫時代替他的角色
What's happening?
這是怎麼回事
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
對不起對不起對不起對不起
Since it's come to this,
既然已經是這種狀況了
at least I must become their Cupid!
至少得成為他們的邱比特才行
-So, madam. -Madam?
-那麼夫人 -什麼夫人
Shall we begin?
我們可以開始了嗎
Ah, yes.
啊 可以
-Sir. -Sir…
-老爺 -老爺…
What kind of date would you like to have with the woman you like?
請問您希望和喜歡的女性 進行怎樣的約會呢
I'd like to go see a movie.
我會想和她去看電影呢
I always go alone,
平常我總是一個人去
so I would be very happy if we could go together.
如果能兩個人一起去看的話 我會很高興的
The matchmaking is progressing smoothly.
相親有在順利進行呢
There should be no need to worry.
這樣應該就不用擔心了
To go see a movie!
竟然是看電影
The cinema… The couple's seat…
電影院…情侶座…
In the dim light.
趁著昏暗…
I'm so shy.
我好害羞
You're about to become a demon, Akagami!
你看起來好像修羅啊 赤神
No, no, I'm Cupid.
不行不行 我是邱比特
What do you usually do on your day off?
那麼一般休假的時候 您都是怎麼度過的呢
I go to the hot springs to relax.
我會去泡溫泉放鬆一下呢
Hot! Springs!
溫 泉
Can I get in with you?
要和我一起泡嗎
HEAVENLY MATCH Akagami, are you okay?
(天作之合) 赤神 你沒事吧
I'm fine, don't worry.
我沒事 妳不用擔心
May I ask, sir,
請問老爺
what are your wishes after getting married?
您結婚以後 有什麼願望嗎
I want to have about ten children.
我想要大概十個左右的孩子呢
I want a baby.
我想給你生個寶寶
Akagami!
赤神
I'm sorry for causing you trouble.
對不起 給您添麻煩了
As you'd expect from Miss Aoba's friend.
沒事 不愧是蒼葉小姐妳的朋友呢
Though I don't know why he is here,
雖然我不知道他為什麼會出現在這裡
I'm sure he is not here to cause trouble.
但我能肯定他絕不是來給妳添亂的
I have full trust in my ability to judge people.
我對看人這點還是挺有自信的
He must be genuinely worried about you.
他一定是打從心底在擔心您吧
After all, his words and deeds are without a shred of deceit.
畢竟他的言行不摻一絲謊言
Deceit?
謊言嗎
Remember, Yuzuki,
記住哦 結月
lying is bad.
撒謊是不好的哦
Indeed, lying is wrong.
果然 騙人還是不對的
What's the matter?
您怎麼了
Mr. Kijou, I'm sorry.
鬼城先生 對不起
Actually,
我其實
I have no plans to get married.
並沒有結婚的打算
So you are looking for an abbot
妳是想找一個擁有住持資格的男人
to inherit Mikazuki Temple?
來繼承三日月寺嗎
Is that why you came for matchmaking?
所以為此妳才要相親
I know my motives aren't pure, but…
我也覺得我動機不純 但是…
It's fine. He's a monk anyway.
沒差啦 反正對方也是和尚
It's no problem to have matchmaking in name only.
相親只走個形式也沒什麼問題吧
But…
但是…
HEAD TEMPLE The key is to buy some time before you become a nun.
(總寺院) 關鍵就是在妳成為尼姑之前幫妳爭取時間
So, you can just stay engaged,
那麼妳就和對方停留在訂婚階段
and break it off after three years.
三年後再毀約就行了
Isn't that kind of like fraud?
那豈不是有點詐騙的感覺嗎
What are you talking about?
妳說什麼呢
You're giving that man a dream of marrying a beautiful girl.
妳都讓那個人 做了和美少女結婚的美夢了
No, this is definitely fraud.
不不 這就是詐騙吧
If you do fall in love, you can get married too.
妳要是真的看上對方
What if he is in a hurry to get married?
如果對方急著結婚呢
I want to finish my studies first.
“人家想先完成學業呢”
You can just brush him off with that.
妳只要用這種話搪塞過去就行了
I see, I'll try it.
我明白了 我會去試試
That's the spirit.
很好 就是這個氣勢
Give those unpopular, unwanted monks a nice dream.
讓那些不受歡迎的剩僧 做一場虛無縹緲的夢吧
Kiki, did something happen between you and some monks?
嬉嬉姐 妳和和尚之間 究竟發生過什麼
I see, you mean…
原來如此 也就是說
To prevent the temple from closing down, you want someone who can help you, right?
妳需要的是能夠避免廢寺的夥伴嗎
Yes.
是的
That's why you came to the matchmaking.
為此妳才前來相親
I'm really sorry! I know it's terrible to lie.
真的非常對不起 我也知道撒謊不好
But,
但是
I know this is a shameless request,
雖然我很清楚這是個厚顏無恥的要求
but could you please get engaged with me?
但能不能請您和我訂婚呢
Please give me… give us some time.
請給我…
HEAVENLY MATCH You're a very honest person.
妳還真是個坦誠的人呢
I like people like you.
(天作之合) 我很欣賞像妳這樣的人
But you're still a child.
但妳還是個孩子
As far as I know,
據我所知
Mikazuki Temple has been lacking funds and manpower for many years.
三日月寺多年欠缺資金 人手也不夠
I heard they don't even have money to properly repair the main hall.
據說連正殿都沒錢好好修繕
I…
那個…
Can you satisfy the believers who come to worship with that?
妳們這樣
You can't save others when you can't even save yourself.
連妳自己都顧不上了
Keeping the temple going
就算妳讓寺廟延續下去
won't make anyone happy.
也不會讓任何人得到幸福
The person who made the decision to abandon the temple
做出廢寺決定的人
probably thought the same way.
恐怕也是這樣想的吧
Anyone…
任何人…
But they…
但是大家…
Face the reality.
請看清現實吧
Mikazuki Temple has no value to protect.
三日月寺沒有任何守護的價值
Even so, I want to inherit that…
即便如此 我也要繼承那所…
Is it because of my family's debt?
沒想到我家的欠款
If the situation has deteriorated to this point,
會讓事情惡化到如此的地步
at least let me use this life
至少讓我用這條命
to redeem the reputation of Mikazuki Temple.
來挽回三日月寺的形象吧
That would make it even worse, Akagami.
那樣形象反而會更差啊 赤神
Sir,
老爺
can we start the matchmaking again?
能不能請您重新審視這場相親呢
Your name is Akagami, right?
你是叫赤神 對吧
It's not a bad thing for you to abandon the temple.
對於你來說 廢寺也不是什麼壞事哦
You can repay the debt slowly.
你家的欠款只要慢慢還就行了
Without the temple, you don't have to do forced labor there.
如果寺廟不在了 你也不用勉強自己在那裡勞動了
I see, for Akagami…
對啊 這對赤神來說…
Then we'll end this matter here.
那麼這件事就到此為止了
I told you, the Mikazuki Temple is no longer…
我說 三日月寺已經沒有必要…
That temple and Miss Yuzuki
那所寺廟和結月小姐
saved me twice.
曾經拯救過我兩次
Akagami.
赤神
That temple is not
那所寺廟絕不是
without value.
毫無價值的
You mean we should keep it?
你的意思是那所寺廟應該延續嗎
Yes.
是的
Even if it means Miss Yuzuki has to work harder?
即使這會讓結月小姐更加辛苦 也沒關係嗎
Running a temple is no easy task!
經營寺廟絕對沒你想像的那麼簡單
Not just her,
不只是她
it will also cause trouble for her family and believers.
也會給她的家人還有施主造成困擾
What if it fails? What if the situation keeps getting worse?
萬一失敗了呢 要是狀況繼續惡化了呢
What if she can't endure it anymore?
當她撐不下去的時候怎麼辦呢
I will support her.
我會支持她
Oh, can you promise?
哦 那麼你敢發誓嗎
Can you swear to make Aoba Yuzuki happy till death do you part?
你願意發誓
I swear!
我願意
Can you swear to be with her in sickness and in health?
你願意發誓 無論健康還是生病
I swear!
我願意
Wait… this isn't…
等…這不是…
Can you swear that, from now on, you will always consider each other,
你願意從此以後
and build a happy family?
都為對方著想
I swear!
我願意
A…proposal…
求…求婚…
HEAVENLY MATCH Then show me
(天作之合) 那就請你們展現出來吧
the value of Mikazuki Temple.
三日月寺的價值
Let's see if your naive ideal
看看你們天真的理想
can defeat the harsh reality.
能否戰勝嚴酷的現實
Alright, Miss Aoba Yuzuki.
好了 蒼葉結月小姐
Yes!
我在
I accept the engagement.
我接受與妳訂婚的提議
But, I'm only lending you my name.
不過 我只是將名字借給你們而已
Thank you very much.
非常感謝
Houan.
峯安
About abandoning the temple,
廢寺那件事
I have asked you to convince them, right?
我應該拜託過你讓她們接受的吧
Because there's a very interesting person, I couldn't help but…
因為有個很有趣的孩子在 所以我忍不住就…
You took an interest in him too, didn't you?
您也對他很感興趣吧
That's why you got him involved in this matchmaking.
所以您才把他也牽扯進這場相親裡
Right, Abbot Aoba?
對吧 蒼葉大僧正
Akagami,
赤神
is he the son of that man?
他是那個男人的兒子嗎
CONTENTMENT BRINGS HAPPINESS (TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-)
(知足者常樂) ( 妙廟美少女)
We didn't catch the bus.
看來我們趕不上公車呢
Let's just walk to the station then.
就這樣走到車站去吧
I'm sorry for all the things that happened.
抱歉哦 發生了這麼多事
What do you mean?
妳指的是什麼
By the way, it's great that the date is successful.
話說回來 相親能順利結束真是太好了
So it's just an engagement, not marriage?
只是訂婚而不是真的結婚嗎
In that case,
那就表示
I won't need to move out of the temple.
我可以不用從寺裡搬出去囉
Of course.
當然啦
That's great!
太好了
Miss Yuzuki?
結月小姐
I'm sorry.
對不起
I don't know how to face you right now.
我現在不知道該用什麼表情面對你
Thank you, Akagami.
謝謝你 赤神
Tears in your eyes, cheeks flushed.
淚眼汪汪 面頰通紅
Why are you spying?
你為什麼要偷看呀
Are you not feeling well?
妳身體不適嗎
Not at all, idiot!
才不是呢 笨蛋
TRAINS ON PLATFORM TWO TODAY'S OPERATION HAS ENDED
(二號月台出發的電車) (今日營運已結束)
The last train departing from this station
由本站出發的末班電車
has already left.
已經發車
The exit will be closed soon.
出入口即將關閉
Please leave the station
請還在站內的旅客
as quickly as possible.
迅速離開本站
-Let's call a taxi. -Right!
-我們叫計程車吧 -對哦
There are no taxis at all.
根本就沒計程車啊
There isn't a single car on the road.
路上連一輛車都沒有
And my phone is dead.
手機也沒電了
Did you bring your phone?
你帶手機了嗎
I smashed it a long time ago.
很久之前被我摔碎了
Why would you do that?
為什麼啊
What should we do? It's starting to get cold.
怎麼辦 開始變冷了
Ow!
好痛
My feet hurt.
我的腳磨破了
This won't do. We need to find a place to rest.
這樣不行 我們還是得找個地方休息一下
SILK ROAD, AIM FOR NIRVANA LOVE HOTEL
(絲綢之路 超越涅槃) (愛情旅館)
No, no, no!
不行不行不行
This is not an invitation.
這不是在邀請我去那裡
This is definitely not an invitation, Akagami Akemitsu.
這絕對不是在邀請我 赤神明光
So, calm down, my worldly desires.
所以平靜下來吧 我的雜念
Akagami,
赤神
should we go take a look?
我們要不要過去看看
Miss Yuzuki!
結月小姐
SILK ROAD, AIM FOR NIRVANA LOVE HOTEL
(絲綢之路 超越涅槃) (愛情旅館)
What a frivolous thought!
妳這是什麼輕浮的想法
No, I don't mean anything weird!
不不 我沒有奇怪的意思
Look, there are no other hotels around here.
你看 這附近也沒有其他店了
That's not the problem here!
我說的並不是這個問題
ROOM 205, REST 1000, STAY 2000 A young man and woman.
一對年輕男女
Just casually checking into a love hotel.
(205號房)(休息1000)(住宿2000) 就這麼隨意地入住愛情旅館
We checked in nonetheless!
最後還是登記入住了啊
Looks amazing, Akagami!
好厲害哦 赤神
Yeah.
是啊
It's more luxurious than I thought!
比我想像的要華麗很多
Indeed.
沒錯
It seems we can order food here.
這裡好像還能點餐呢
You're in a good mood, Miss Yuzuki.
就是這種調調 結月小姐
If we keep this up, things won't get weird.
這樣就不會出現什麼奇怪的氛圍了
We can even sing K and play games.
這裡還能唱KTV和打遊戲呢
There's even karaoke and games.
只要不看那邊的牆壁就行
Akagami, look at this!
赤神 你快看
COSPLAY, FREE TO RENT There are even costumes for cosplay!
(各類角色扮演 免費租借服裝) 還有角色扮演用的衣服呢
Miss Yuzuki!
結月小姐
Why?
為什麼
Why must you stir up my worldly desires?
妳為什麼要刺激我的雜念
Calm down.
冷靜
Miss Yuzuki is probably trying to lighten the mood.
結月小姐應該是為了緩和氣氛…
We can also watch movies.
這裡還能看電影
Even AV is free to watch.
而且AV也可以隨便看呢
Worldly desires, begone!
雜念退散
WORLDLY DESIRES, BEGONE Sorry, I got carried away.
(雜念退散 雜念退散) 抱歉 我鬧過頭了
Akagami,
赤神
you go take a shower first.
你先去沖個澡吧
She really meant it!
她真的有那個意思
No, what nonsense am I talking?
不對不對 我說什麼蠢話呢
Why would Miss Yuzuki seduce me?
結月小姐怎麼可能會誘惑我呢
Asking me to take a shower first,
她讓我先來洗澡
she must be caring for me and letting me have a rest.
肯定是在關心我 想讓我消解疲勞
That's right, there's definitely no wicked motive behind.
沒錯 這絕對不是出自那種 不純潔的原因
Miss Yuzuki, I'm done.
結月小姐 我洗完了
What's wrong?
妳怎麼了
Nothing.
我沒事
I'll go now.
我去洗了哦
Miss Yuzuki was watching AV?
結…結月小姐竟然在看AV
No, no, no.
不可能不可能
She wanted to watch AV, is that why she asked me to take a shower first?
她難道是想偷偷看AV 所以才讓我先去洗澡的嗎
How could this be?
怎麼會這樣
That's right, Akagami.
(正是如此) 沒錯哦 赤神
Sis Yuzuki can be quite pervy too.
結月姐姐也是很色的呢
And she's the type who keeps it to herself.
(正是如此) 而且她還是悶騷的類型
What should I do?
我到底該怎麼辦才好
What's there to worry about?
這有什麼可煩惱的
AKAGAMI LEWDMITSU Is there any other option other than to pounce on her?
(赤神色光) 除了推倒她還有別的選項嗎
ENLIGHTENED AKEMITSU Isn't that what she wished for?
(笨神明光) 難道這不也是她所期待的嗎
This is where you need to show your manliness!
這裡就該展現你的男子氣概了
You can't let the girl feel embarrassed.
不可以讓女生蒙羞哦
Their opinions actually align.
他們倆意見竟然一致了
You need to follow your heart.
你要遵從自己的內心
You want to become one with her too, don't you?
你也想和她結合為一吧
Shut up!
閉嘴
Violence is not right.
暴力是不對的呢
Why not take the step into adulthood?
不如就登上大人的階梯吧
Damn it!
可惡
I've already sworn to support her.
我都發誓要支持她了
I…I want to
我…我要
protect her.
守護她
So that's what AV is.
AV原來是那樣的啊
The bathroom is so spacious.
浴室好寬敞
What is it for?
是做什麼用的呢
I can't believe we really ended up staying in a love hotel.
沒想到我真的住進愛情旅館了
What should I do? what should I do?
怎麼辦 怎麼辦
Anyway, I need to warm up and calm down first.
總之我先暖暖身子冷靜一下吧
Why do I feel even more shy
我怎麼冷靜下來以後
after calming down?!
就感覺更加害羞了呀
What am I getting excited about?
我到底在興奮個什麼勁啊
I let Akagami stay in too,
而且還帶著赤神也住了進來
doesn't it look like I'm expecting something to happen?
這不變成我好像 在期待什麼事情一樣嗎
This could cause a misunderstanding.
這樣會引起誤會的吧
How should I face Akagami from now on?
今後我該怎樣面對赤神呢
I will support her.
我會支持她
I swear!
我願意
If
如果
Akagami sincerely
赤神認真地
asks me,
向我要求的話
I…
我…
Please rest assured.
請你放心
Miss Yuzuki, there won't be any danger for you.
結月小姐 這樣妳就絕對不會有危險了
Please rest well.
還請好好休息
Miss Yuzuki, why are you putting a blindfold on me?
結月小姐 為什麼給我戴眼罩
Miss Yuzuki? Hey, Miss Yuzuki?
結月小姐 喂 結月小姐
I can't even go to the bathroom like this.
這樣我都沒辦法上廁所了
Miss Yuzuki?
結月小姐
Hey, are you still there?
喂 妳還在吧
SILK ROAD, AIM FOR NIRVANA, LOVE HOTEL Idiot.
笨蛋
I hit it.
(下集 你該怎樣對我負責呢) 射中了哦
I've got it!
有了呀
You're talking about archery, right?
(下集 你該怎樣對我負責呢) 妳說的是弓道吧
You're staring too intently.
妳盯得太緊了呢
(Next episode: How Will You Take Responsibility for Me?)
(下集 你該怎樣對我負責呢)